This XML file does not appear to have any style information associated with it. The document tree is shown below.
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
    <link href="/fortheloveofnifty/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
    <link href="/fortheloveofnifty/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <updated>2021-05-10T16:57:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>/fortheloveofnifty/feed.xml</id>
    <title type="html">For The Love Of Nifty</title>
    <subtitle>This blog is for those who won't work for money but their money will work for them Heading for a
        financially independent generation and a Money Smart India</subtitle>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">P17-Debt-Funds</title>
        <link href="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/19/2020-05-19-Debt-funds.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"
            title="P17-Debt-Funds" />
        <published>2020-05-19T17:30:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-05-19T17:30:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/19/2020-05-19-Debt-funds</id>
        <content type="html" xml:base="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/19/2020-05-19-Debt-funds.html">
            <style>
                header {
                    background-color: rgba(249, 241, 241, 0.7);
                    font-weight: bolder;
                    font-size: larger;
                    font-family: fantasy;
                }

                div {
                    background-image: url("https://i.postimg.cc/y6fw6m3Y/yoann-siloine-dyax-Q-ao-GWY-unsplash.jpg");
                }
            </style>
            <p><strong>post 17</strong> <br /> <strong>Dated</strong>19/5/2020<br /> <strong>Debt Funds</strong> <br />
                <strong>snippet</strong> Today we will find uncover all the major types of debt funds<br /></p>
            <p>Following along our discussion today we will give a look to the safer side. Here we will learn about
                various debt funds and the underlying assets of a debt fund. <br /> The debt funds can be of several
                types and can hold various instruments as their underlying assets, these are as follows<br /><br /></p>
            <ol>
                <li>These can be classified based on the time duration of their scope that can be planed according to a
                    <strong>smart Goal</strong> <br /><br /> A) <strong>Long Duration Funds</strong><br /> Long Duration
                    Fund : These mutual funds select bonds/debt for investment such that average maturity (remaining)
                    period for portfolio is higher than 7 years. Longer duration funds may provide higher returns but
                    are more sensitive to interest rate changes. <br /></li>
            </ol>
            <p>Suitable For : Investors who want to invest money for longer duration but prefer less riskier assets
                compared to equity funds. <br /><br /> B) <strong>Medium Duration Funds</strong> Medium duration funds
                are debt funds that lend to quality companies for 3 or more years. The longer tenure of loan means these
                funds returns are subject to the interest rate changes that borrowing companies undergo due to positive
                or negative economic cycles over time. These are also more tax-efficient than Bank Fixed Deposits when
                investment tenure is 3 years or more as these funds qualify for <strong>indexation
                    benefit</strong>.<br /> C) ** Short term Funds** These are probably most useful products of debt
                category because these give us a way to park our idle money without any major risk, These lend to
                companies for a period of 1 to 3 years. These funds mostly take exposure only in quality companies that
                have proven record of repaying their loans on time as well as have sufficient cash flows from their
                business operations to justify the borrowing <br /><br /> D) <strong>Liquid Funds</strong> are high
                liquidity open-ended income schemes that invest in debt and money market instruments such as government
                securities, treasury bills and call money among others. These instruments have a maximum maturity period
                of 91 days and are considered safe because they mitigate interest rate volatility risk. These give a
                handsome and cool alternative to a bank account, but a bank give us insurance of 5 lakhs on deposits
                under DICGC (Deposit Insurance and credit guarantee corporation) These don’t give that insurance but are
                still very good at risk mitigation and I would personally favor a liquid fund instead of Savings account
                even if I need to park my money for a week.<br /><br />. E) <strong>Dynamic Bond Funds</strong> These
                are the funds those adjust the time duration of underlying assets according to market status and help
                generating higher returns. Here the role and decision making of a fund manager is very crucial and major
                chunk of performance is based on him.<br /> <br /> F) <strong>Gilt Funds</strong> There are very low
                risk funds that hold gilt securities/ government securities issued by the central government and state
                governments, hence these are seen with minimum risk and these too give handsome returns of about 13-15%
                annually.<br /><br /></p>
            <p>Now after reading about majority of the flavors we often get confused about which to select and when to
                select. This dilemma can be solved by analyzing our initial smart goal. We need to analyze the amount of
                return that we need and we have to analyze the risk taking capabilities of our emotional self and our
                goal. Like for a Goal I would invest heavily in <strong>Equity</strong> in the initial phase because I
                would have a lot of time if anything goes wrong and I would have a chance to remake my strategy if
                anything goes wrong. But this wont be the case if the due date is just 6 months, and I’ve lost a major
                chunk in equity because I can not wait for market to recover. To avoid this we should follow risk
                mitigation where we keep increasing the debt segment of our investments as we approach our deadline. See
                investing money is like making <strong>Halwa</strong>, we have to keep on mixing it or else it will burn
                and get distasteful. <br /> Hope this gives you something new<br /><br /> Thanks for reading<br />
                Anubhav Gupta.</p>
            <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
            <script>
                (function () { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE var d = document, s = d.createElement('script'); s.src = 'https://https-gupta-anubhav12-github-io-fortheloveofnifty.disqus.com/embed.js'; s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date()); (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s); })(); 
            </script> <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments
                    powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
        </content>
        <author>
            <name>Anubhav Gupta</name>
        </author>
        <summary type="html" />
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">P15-Mutual-Funds</title>
        <link href="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/16/2020-05-16-Mutual-Funds.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"
            title="P15-Mutual-Funds" />
        <published>2020-05-16T17:30:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-05-16T17:30:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/16/2020-05-16-Mutual-Funds</id>
        <content type="html" xml:base="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/16/2020-05-16-Mutual-Funds.html">
            <style>
                header {
                    background-color: rgba(249, 241, 241, 0.7);
                    font-weight: bolder;
                    font-size: larger;
                    font-family: fantasy;
                }

                div {
                    background-image: url("https://i.postimg.cc/y6fw6m3Y/yoann-siloine-dyax-Q-ao-GWY-unsplash.jpg");
                }
            </style>
            <p><strong>post 15</strong> <br /> <strong>Dated</strong>16/5/2020<br /> <strong>Mutual Funds</strong>
                <br /> <strong>snippet</strong> Mutual Funds have a lot to offer read more to find out <br /></p>
            <p>Mutual funds are probably the best option for mediocre investments and they are affordable and easy to
                learn. Mutual funds as said earlier are like a ice cream studio with a lot of flavours. These flavours
                offer us to invest in a variety of debt and equity type funds <br /> But wait no one might have told you
                that you can also use mutual funds like a savings <strong>Bank Account</strong>. Banks give us around
                3.5 percent after saving their spread on a regular savings account but a Liquid Debt fund can give you
                about 6-7% with an insta withdraw facility where we can withdraw the money in half an hour of order
                placement.<br /> Hence we can use mutual funds like a Bank account with selective funds like Liquid
                funds that invest out money in instruments of money market like treasury bills and short term
                G-Secs.<br /><br /> Mutual Funds are also an alertnative of FD, yes a low duration debt or guilt fund is
                normally risk free and gives returns ranging from 8-11% whereas the Bank FDR barely crosses 6% in rare
                cases.<br /> there’s still more in the Ice cream studio, You can get a <strong>SIP</strong>(systematic
                Investment Plan) registered with a mutual fund of your choice and can get a nice investment portfolio.
                See a SIP is not a mutual fund but an investment strategy.In a SIP we promise to pay a agreed amount
                each month to generate a saving corpus for a goal like- Child’s education or getting a house or a car.
                But the goal should be <strong>SMART</strong>. The sip works on the principal of average pricing and is
                shown by the following example:-<br /><br /> One day <strong>Bunty</strong> bought 4 pencils worth $10
                rach and he expected the price to rise to 11 in subsequent days. Ladoo on other hand just brought a
                single pencil and waited for next day, next day the price rose to 11, Bunty was happy to see
                profits,Ladoo patiently bought another pemcil for $11. the next day price fell to rs 8 and laddu again
                bought a pencil, Bunty at this time started to worry for his investment, the next day price went to $9
                and Ladoo got another pencil.<br /> now if we analyse the position of Bunty, He has invested 40 rupees
                for 4 pencils that today value around 36, Whereas Laduu has bought 4 pencils for <strong>38</strong> and
                the today’s value is of 36. so who stands in a better position.<br /> this can now be seen as a case
                between mutual funds where one investor does a huge impulsive lumpsum transaction whereas the wiser is
                patient and investes periodically, Clearly now when the price of pencil will reach $10 the
                <strong>initial value</strong> laddoo would be in profit whereas bunty would be at a neutral
                position.<br /><br /> But I’ve heared that money gets locked in mutual funds??<br /> Well there are
                several types of funds that define their own terms of operation that should be read and anayzed before
                investing, like<br /></p>
            <ol>
                <li>open/Close ended funds: some funds are close ended hence they allow entry for a short period of
                    time, exmaple a fund gets opened for a window of a week then it would be available for purchase on
                    only those days, whereas in a open ended fund there is anytime entry.<br /></li>
                <li>Exit Load : This thing is a must to check before investing in a fund. The exit load is a percent of
                    penalty that would be levied on a your investment or a part of your investment if you withdraw
                    before a particular tenure, this can be between 15 days to several years.<br /></li>
                <li>Lockin Period: If there is a lockin period termed in a fund then that would lock your amount and you
                    can not wihdraw before the lockin, Sometimes there is a partial lockin like you cannot withdraw more
                    than 40% of amount before a period.<br /></li>
            </ol>
            <p>So mutual funds sahi to hai but<br /> Read all scheme related documents carefully<br /><br /> Happy
                investing and stay safe.</p>
            <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
            <script>
                (function () { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE var d = document, s = d.createElement('script'); s.src = 'https://https-gupta-anubhav12-github-io-fortheloveofnifty.disqus.com/embed.js'; s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date()); (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s); })(); 
            </script> <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments
                    powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
        </content>
        <author>
            <name>Anubhav Gupta</name>
        </author>
        <summary type="html" />
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">P16-Flavoured-Funds</title>
        <link href="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/16/Flavours-of-funds.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"
            title="P16-Flavoured-Funds" />
        <published>2020-05-16T17:30:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-05-16T17:30:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/16/Flavours-of-funds</id>
        <content type="html" xml:base="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/16/Flavours-of-funds.html">
            <style>
                header {
                    background-color: rgba(249, 241, 241, 0.7);
                    font-weight: bolder;
                    font-size: larger;
                    font-family: fantasy;
                }

                div {
                    background-image: url("https://i.postimg.cc/y6fw6m3Y/yoann-siloine-dyax-Q-ao-GWY-unsplash.jpg");
                }
            </style>
            <p><strong>post 16</strong> <br /> <strong>Dated</strong>18/5/2020<br /> <strong>Mutual Funds</strong>
                <br /> <strong>snippet</strong> Today we will find uncover all the major types of funds and their
                investment options<br /></p>
            <p>So we now have got <strong>Smart goals</strong> and now it’s the time to work for them. To plan for a
                financial goal we need to start saving….Rather investing as I would say, Because savings won’t grow your
                money rather inflation will eat away, So <strong>don’t save</strong> but <strong>invest</strong><br />
            </p>
            <p>Now we need to agree upon a fund that can meet our required returns for a goal, Now if we are planning a
                long term asset we must consider the last 6 months for lower return of about 7%, Because when we reach
                near our goals, We should shift our money from high risk aggressive equity fund to a safer and stable
                debt oriented funds. This is a healthy practice to avoid last term uncertanities and failure of our
                <strong>smart Goal</strong> because a goal failing won’t be smart enough.<br /><br /></p>
            <p>The several major types of Funds for consideration are<br /> <strong>Equity Oriented</strong> for Long
                Term These are generally aggressive and have higher risk so these are apt for initial long term
                investments that can be used to raise aggressive returns. These should be avoid during last time period
                of our Goal <br /> there are several calssification for a fund in Equity market but these are generally
                classified based on the market cap (<strong>size</strong>) of companies involved.<br /></p>
            <ol>
                <li>
                    <p>Large Cap Funds funds investing in Large cap companies are referred to large capThe market
                        capitalization of these companies is very high – above Rs20,000cr. Large-cap companies have
                        strong market presence and their stocks are generally considered to be very safe (low risk).
                        Most of these companies regularly disclose information through media, such as newspapers. In
                        other words, information on large-cap companies is very readily available. <br /></p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Mid cap Funds These Funds have mid cap companies in their portfolio Mid-cap companies are
                        considerably smaller than large-cap companies in all fields of comparison – revenue,
                        profitability, employees, client base, etc.</p>
                </li>
            </ol>
            <p>What attracts investors to mid-cap stocks is the possibility of investing in a company that could become
                an overnight success. Mid-cap companies have a tremdendous scope for growth and can potentially give
                higher returns in the 3-5-year investment horizon.<br /></p>
            <ol>
                <li>
                    <p>Small Cap Funds These funds have companies which are smaller in size and revenue Most small-cap
                        companies are either start-up enterprises or companies in the development stage. Understandably,
                        they have low revenues and a small number of employees and clients. Information on these
                        companies isn’t easily available to all. This is exactly what makes small-cap stocks a big
                        winner for investors with a long investment horizon and a moderate-to-high risk appetite – not a
                        lot of people know about the stock! However due to their nature, small-cap stocks are considered
                        to be a highly risky investment</p>
                </li>
                <li>Multi Cap Fund This is a special mixed flavour of above all three and can have different ratios
                    according to your needs,You can select one.</li>
                <li>Focused Funds These are several funds having some selected companies to focus their investment on,
                    Axis Focused 25 fund, HDFC top 100 fund.</li>
            </ol>
            <p>Now there are several funds those have their companies selectted based on a specific type of companies,
                like those of a specific sector of economy,<br /> several examples are -</p>
            <ol>
                <li>Sectoral Pharma: Investing in only pharma companies</li>
                <li>Thematic Energy: Investinf in energy corporations etc<br /></li>
            </ol>
            <p>There are a lot more flavours, Keep your savoury eyes ready tomorrow for next dose @5:30 PM.<br /> happy
                Investing<br /></p>
            <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
            <script>
                (function () { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE var d = document, s = d.createElement('script'); s.src = 'https://https-gupta-anubhav12-github-io-fortheloveofnifty.disqus.com/embed.js'; s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date()); (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s); })(); 
            </script> <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments
                    powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
        </content>
        <author>
            <name>Anubhav Gupta</name>
        </author>
        <summary type="html" />
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">P14-It’s-All-Mutual</title>
        <link href="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/15/2020-05-15-It's-All-Mutual.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"
            title="P14-It’s-All-Mutual" />
        <published>2020-05-15T17:30:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-05-15T17:30:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/15/2020-05-15-It's-All-Mutual</id>
        <content type="html" xml:base="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/15/2020-05-15-It's-All-Mutual.html">
            <style>
                header {
                    background-color: rgba(249, 241, 241, 0.7);
                    font-weight: bolder;
                    font-size: larger;
                    font-family: fantasy;
                }

                div {
                    background-image: url("https://i.postimg.cc/y6fw6m3Y/yoann-siloine-dyax-Q-ao-GWY-unsplash.jpg");
                }
            </style>
            <p><strong>post 14</strong> <br /> <strong>Dated</strong>15/5/2020<br /> <strong>Mutual Funds</strong>
                <br /> <strong>snippet</strong> Today we will introduce the concept of Mutual funds<br /></p>
            <p>We all want to invest our savings somewhere and want our money to work for us but we are somewhat afraid
                of Stock Market due to it’s volatility and senstivity, But what if there is a reasonably safe and easier
                approach to invest money and generate profits??<br /> <br /> Let’s see the basics of a Mutual fund :
                <br /><br /> as we have talked earlier that investing in a company requires deep knowledge of
                fundamental analysis and a handsome amount of time to analyze a single company. It also requires a
                constant watch on an invested company for it’s performance. <br /><br /> But what if we oursource this
                task to someone else and create a common fund collected from a large community of investors, Well this
                healthhy pool of money is called a Mutual Fund that have mutual contributions from a lot of
                people.<br /></p>
            <p>Now what is the benefit of this common collection and who is responsible of it’s maintainance??<br /></p>
            <ol>
                <li>
                    <p>Sometimes in market we cannnot purchase shares of a company that are too pricy like MRF tyres
                        stands alone at 58,200 as on 15-05-2020. but a mediocre investor cannot atfford this price for a
                        single share and has will to invest in company!!<br /> so in laymans terms one can buy a part of
                        share by investing in mutual funds because when a lot of investors with a common thought pool in
                        money, The targeted share becomes affordable due to collection of corpus.<br /><br /></p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>As we have seen the fund management is outsorced and investor has a little to do in research and
                        analysis once he finds an Trusted AMC.<br /><br /></p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p><strong>AMC</strong> is Asset management Company and is responsible for creation of a Fund
                        portfolio that contains selected companies and debt instruments and is precisely balanced
                        according to a goal and vision of <strong>Fund Manager</strong>. In return fund manager charges
                        a small amount for their services called <strong>TER</strong> or Total Expense Ratio which is
                        generally .2%-1% of the investment and is quite reasonable too.<br /><br /></p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>This takes us to fourth point <strong>never keep all eggs in same Basket</strong> mutual funds
                        provide this service by defining a portfolio according to our investment needs with a mix of
                        balance of each aspect.<br /><br /></p>
                </li>
            </ol>
            <p>Mutual Funds are like a ice cream shop from a child’s fantasy with all the possible flavours and
                sometimes it becomes difficult to choose one :).<br /> first of all let’s again visit the concept of
                Equity and Debt.<br /></p>
            <p>now in equity we (or AMC on our behalf) gets a partial ownership of that company and we are entitled to
                both profits and lossed equally hence Investments in Equity are riskier comparatively.<br /> But in the
                case of debt there is no loss sharing. Company has to pay us the money back with our interest hence this
                segment is nearly risk free.<br /> Now a mutual fund portfolio is ike a icecream cone which is selected
                according to our taste and risk taking abilities, Some funds are Equity Focussed and some are Debt
                oriented. Now for high risk equity funds can give returns as high as 25%-30% in good functioning of
                market and can also pose losses for same.<br /> whereas the debt segment is somewhat stable with about
                8-12% of return annually…..It’s still better than your old <strong>Bank FDR</strong>.<br /> Now a
                perfect mix of these two broad options is reffered to as a hybrid fund.<br /><br /> Another
                classification of mutual funds is wether they pay <strong>dividend</strong> or not! if they do then they
                are called dividend funds and have a defined frequency of paying dividend<br /> if they don’t then they
                are called the growth option, Here the value of <strong>NAV</strong> appreciates and we have to sell
                them to obtain profit<br /><br /> also to be noted that the mutual funds are better for investment
                wether it be short term or long term because they are not traded like shares on a stock exchange. To
                avoid trading mentality the price <strong>NAV</strong> is daily released in evening about 10Pm instead
                of updating it every second as of shares on an exchange.<br /> But what is a NAV :: it stands for Net
                Asset Value, it is the basic price of a single unit of a mutual fund. Also unlike shares mutual funds
                can be purchased for less than a unit. Example if I have less money I can purchase 0.25 units of a
                Mutual fund too. Hence these are customisable. <br /><br /></p>
            <p>Hope you will also experience sweetness of this icecream studio<br /><br /> Happy Investing <br /> This
                is just an effort to share something I have during this Lockdown stay safe and keep learning</p>
            <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
            <script>
                (function () { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE var d = document, s = d.createElement('script'); s.src = 'https://https-gupta-anubhav12-github-io-fortheloveofnifty.disqus.com/embed.js'; s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date()); (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s); })(); 
            </script> <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments
                    powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
        </content>
        <author>
            <name>Anubhav Gupta</name>
        </author>
        <summary type="html" />
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">P13-Smart-Goal</title>
        <link href="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/14/2020-05-14-Smart-Goal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"
            title="P13-Smart-Goal" />
        <published>2020-05-14T17:30:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-05-14T17:30:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/14/2020-05-14-Smart-Goal</id>
        <content type="html" xml:base="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/14/2020-05-14-Smart-Goal.html">
            <style>
                header {
                    background-color: rgba(249, 241, 241, 0.7);
                    font-weight: bolder;
                    font-size: larger;
                    font-family: fantasy;
                }

                div {
                    background-image: url("https://i.postimg.cc/y6fw6m3Y/yoann-siloine-dyax-Q-ao-GWY-unsplash.jpg");
                }
            </style>
            <p><strong>post 13</strong> <br /> <strong>Dated</strong>14/5/2020<br /> <strong>Setting a Smart
                    Goal</strong> <br /> <strong>snippet</strong> Today we will explore the ideal and essential
                feratures of a goal<br /></p>
            <p>Everyone want’s to be rich in this world and has a goal to be rich. But the term rich is comparative and
                is ambiguous. Having a Car and to own home can be a state of being rich for one whereas owning a MNC can
                be the defination of richness of other.<br /><br /> so in order to work for a Goal, we need to first set
                it up properly. Here we define the smartness behind a SMART Goal which would help you set your
                goals.<br /></p>
            <p>SMART: c<br />an be seen as : Specific, Measurable, Achievable Realistic and Time bound<br /><br /> we
                all might have some goals, Test those on these aspects and decide if you have a Smart goal or you need
                to modify it for being smart.<br /> <strong>Specific</strong> means to set a well defined and specific
                goal, Like if I bunty asks his employees to <strong>“get more business”</strong> is lame, whereas to ask
                them to “btain 20% growth of sales by entering new terrirories and explore a new tie up” would be
                specific<br /><br /> <strong>Measurable</strong> means to set a goal with a realistic value, Laddu once
                said to me “<strong>I want a lot of money</strong>” but he didn’t specified How much??. So your Goal
                should be measurable and must have a value that is realisable in market.<br />
                <strong>Achievable</strong> A goal that can be realised in your life only should be counted smart.
                <br /><br /> <strong>Realistic</strong> a goal should be realistic and shouldn’t be a fantasy from your
                dreams, Buying real Estate on Mars is not realistic for this generation at least Sorry Elon :(
                <br /><br /> <strong>Time Bound</strong> Time limit for achieving a goal is very important to avoid
                unecessary procastination. Also it helps you define a timeline and to divide your task into small
                modules.Which combine to form a big giant task. Breaking a Huge problem to small modules and tackling
                those individually over a period of time to add up the results is the smartness in a smart goal.<br />
                After reading the above? is your Goal really smart?? if not set one and work towards it.<br /><br /></p>
            <p>Financial goals are not different and should be considered a problem of reverse engineering.<br /><br />
                say I’ve set a goal to buy an asset worth 15 Lakhs in 5 years<br /> I estimated the returns on me
                investments to be 12% after being normalized for inflation.<br /><br /> but the asset of car would also
                inflate and considering that too I would set a goal of 18 Lakhs.<br /><br /> now I want 18 Lakhs in 5
                years but I am also getting a real interest of 12%.<br /> so I will reverse Engineer the amount of
                monthly investments that I can make. If that monthy amount is fine for me the I can count my goal as
                SMART or else it would be unachievable as of current state.<br /><br /> so I will start a sip with an
                aggressive mutual fund for 22000 a month.<br /> This is the basic crux behind setting and executing
                financial goals in perosnal finance. So calculate and start early to get most out of your money. Goals
                can be set for anything like child’s education, your house, Retirement, etc. Just calculate and analyze
                your needs and wants to invest before you spend. <br /><br /> Happy investing<br /></p>
            <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
            <script>
                (function () { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE var d = document, s = d.createElement('script'); s.src = 'https://https-gupta-anubhav12-github-io-fortheloveofnifty.disqus.com/embed.js'; s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date()); (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s); })(); 
            </script> <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments
                    powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
        </content>
        <author>
            <name>Anubhav Gupta</name>
        </author>
        <summary type="html" />
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">P12-Trading-vs-Investing</title>
        <link href="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/13/2020-05-13-Trading-vs-Investing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"
            title="P12-Trading-vs-Investing" />
        <published>2020-05-13T17:30:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-05-13T17:30:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/13/2020-05-13-Trading-vs-Investing</id>
        <content type="html" xml:base="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/13/2020-05-13-Trading-vs-Investing.html">
            <style>
                header {
                    background-color: rgba(249, 241, 241, 0.7);
                    font-weight: bolder;
                    font-size: larger;
                    font-family: fantasy;
                }

                div {
                    background-image: url("https://i.postimg.cc/y6fw6m3Y/yoann-siloine-dyax-Q-ao-GWY-unsplash.jpg");
                }
            </style>
            <p><strong>post 12</strong> <br /> <strong>Dated</strong>13/5/2020<br /> <strong>Trading vs
                    Investing</strong> <br /> <strong>snippet</strong> Today we will define the fundamental differences
                between trading and investing.<br /></p>
            <p>This is often a general confusion and a public notion that trading and investment are similar terms. But
                these have a lot more subtle differences. lets see this through a plot <br /> <img
                    style="float:left; margin-right: 20px" src="https://i.postimg.cc/4dhBTx5j/Capture.jpg" /></p>
            <p>the general trend of Nifty over the years is more or less growing, But if we zoom in and see, We will see
                a lot of ups and downs,<br /> <img style="float:left; margin-right: 20px"
                    src="https://i.postimg.cc/1XhMR17X/Capturecxrsfdg.jpg" /></p>
            <p>The difference between a trader and investor is the mindset of booking profits, A trader has to trade
                sucessfully between the short term fluctuation of prices but an investor would seek the company to grow
                along with his money. The investor would always plan for a long run and is generally associated with
                lower risk as compared to an investor. Because the longer time slowly averages out the chances of
                risk.<br /> Now the trader has his definitions of time reffered as.<br /></p>
            <ol>
                <li>Intraday: Where a trader purchase or sell some shares and square off within one day (squaring off :
                    within a day coming back to initial holding,like you’ve purchased something and you are required to
                    sell that same day.)<br /></li>
                <li>Swing: Where a trader holds a position for a few days ranging in fortnights.<br /></li>
            </ol>
            <p>But an investor seeks refuge in Long term capital gain and is not affected with daily changes, But
                investor believes in the Fundamental analysis and a strong base of a company, Whereas a trader can
                ignore the fundamental analysis and can even purchase companies that are fundamentally weak but are
                driven by market mentality for a day trade.<br /> now both of these are to be taxed accordingly and the
                Indian taxation defines two types of Taxes, One for each of these:</p>
            <ol>
                <li>Short term capital gains Tax: Here the profit is added to income and person is taxed according to
                    income brecket</li>
                <li>Long term capital gains : If a perosn holds a Equity for more than 1 year or a debt Mutual fund for
                    more than 3 years then this is applicable and this stands at 10% , earlier it was 0% but is recently
                    reintroduced :(.<br /></li>
            </ol>
            <p>Now along with the difference in mentality, there is difference in the analytical approach towards a
                company also. This is seen as below<br /></p>
            <ol>
                <li>
                    <p>Technical Analysis is a analytical approach to study the plot and guess the pattern which a stock
                        might be forming to form a position accordingly,<br /> Here are some interesting patterns<br />
                        <img style="float:left; margin-right: 20px"
                            src="https://i.postimg.cc/6qrcybF0/0_6EW3YFJs2Nw2E5bS_.png" /></p>
                </li>
                <li>But the Investor has not much interest in the daily impuslive movement and investor relies on his
                    own study reffered to as fumdamental analysis which evaluates the company’s basic structure on
                    following bases.<br /></li>
                <li>Profitability Analysis : How well can a company generate profits utilizing its resources</li>
                <li>Liquidity Analysis : How much cash in hand or liquid assets does a company has to continue day to
                    day operations</li>
                <li>Activity Analysis : How efficiently can a company generate sales from capital it employs.</li>
                <li>Solvency Analysis : How efficiently company would covet long term debt</li>
            </ol>
            <p>I hope that you can now clearly differentiate and choose a suited path . either you would invest or trade
                to earn a fortune<br /></p>
            <p>Happy learning</p>
        </content>
        <author>
            <name>Anubhav Gupta</name>
        </author>
        <summary type="html" />
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">P11-Setting-Up-Trade</title>
        <link href="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/12/2020-05-12-Setting-Up-trade.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"
            title="P11-Setting-Up-Trade" />
        <published>2020-05-12T15:20:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-05-12T15:20:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/12/2020-05-12-Setting-Up-trade</id>
        <content type="html" xml:base="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/12/2020-05-12-Setting-Up-trade.html">
            <style>
                header {
                    background-color: rgba(249, 241, 241, 0.7);
                    font-weight: bolder;
                    font-size: larger;
                    font-family: fantasy;
                }

                div {
                    background-image: url("https://i.postimg.cc/y6fw6m3Y/yoann-siloine-dyax-Q-ao-GWY-unsplash.jpg");
                }
            </style>
            <p><strong>post 11</strong> <br /> <strong>Dated</strong>12/5/2020<br /> <strong>Setting Up Trade</strong>
                <br /> <strong>snippet</strong> Today we will explore How as an investor we can purchase Shares<br />
            </p>
            <p>To purchase any shares from the stock exchange we need to have an account with the stock exchange. We
                have seen in previous posts that the trading was changed to electronic form in 1995 after the
                establishment of NSE (National Stock Exchange). The shares that we purchase form stock exchange are
                stored in Demat form (dematerialized form) in a special account called Demat Account. <br /> Like all
                accounts we have are registered with an organisation like a bank for a simple bank account. Here the
                Demat account is registered with an organisation called Depository.<br /> The
                <strong>depository</strong> is an organisation that host your Demat account and is responsible for
                creating dematerialized forms of existing shares if they exist.<br /> There are two depositories
                registered with SEBI in India, these are <strong>CDSL</strong>(central depository services limited) and
                <strong>NSDL</strong> (National securities depository limited ).<br /> But wait Demat account can only
                hold shares like a reserve. In order to conduct the transactions, we need to have a separate account
                called Trading account that holds the money and executes the orders.<br /> In order to open an account,
                we need to approach a broker or an investment firm which on-demand and on completion of all the
                <strong>KYC</strong> (know your customer) norms opens a trading account and provide us with a trading
                login credentials. These can be used on a compatible trading software like NEAT (National Exchange for
                Automated Trading).<br /> There are software and mobile trading apps like Upstox (I have an account with
                them) and Zerodha <strong>I don’t promote any of these</strong> it’s your wish and choice to open an
                account.<br /></p>
            <p>Now to trade efficiency you need three accounts, namely bank account + trading account + Demat account.
                These days the need for all these is being fulfilled by a new concept called 3 in one account that has
                all the features and is less cluttered.</p>
            <p>Happy investing</p>
            <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
            <script>
                (function () { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE var d = document, s = d.createElement('script'); s.src = 'https://https-gupta-anubhav12-github-io-fortheloveofnifty.disqus.com/embed.js'; s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date()); (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s); })(); 
            </script> <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments
                    powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
        </content>
        <author>
            <name>Anubhav Gupta</name>
        </author>
        <summary type="html" />
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">P9-Bunty’s-Listing</title>
        <link href="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/10/2020-05-10-Bunty's-Listing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"
            title="P9-Bunty’s-Listing" />
        <published>2020-05-10T16:52:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-05-10T16:52:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/10/2020-05-10-Bunty's-Listing</id>
        <content type="html" xml:base="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/10/2020-05-10-Bunty's-Listing.html">
            <style>
                header {
                    background-color: rgba(249, 241, 241, 0.7);
                    font-weight: bolder;
                    font-size: larger;
                    font-family: fantasy;
                }

                div {
                    background-image: url("https://i.postimg.cc/y6fw6m3Y/yoann-siloine-dyax-Q-ao-GWY-unsplash.jpg");
                }
            </style>
            <p><strong>post 9</strong> <br /> <strong>Dated</strong>10/5/2020<br /> <strong>Bunty’s Listing</strong>
                <br /> <strong>snippet</strong> Today we will see How bunty can Register his company with Stock
                Exchange<br /></p>
            <p>In the previous post we saw that Bunty raised his capital for his company form his friends and
                acquitances (this selling of shares to less than 50 investors is called <strong>Private
                    Placement</strong>). But now Bunty’s Company has grown more and he needs more capital for Expansion
                of his company. Well he can now get his company listed on the stock exchange to sell shares to common
                public instead of just selling to his friends.<br /> The issuing of Shares in market for the first time
                for general public is called IPO or <strong>Initial Public Offering</strong> this is done in Primary
                market.Stock market is divided into two parts :- Primary Market and Secondary market. The first issues
                are released in The Primary Market and the trading is done in secondary Market.<br /><br /></p>
            <p>So to generate an IPO Bunty has to follow a proceedure and has to obey several norms, Let’s
                see<br /><br /></p>
            <p>IPO can be released Through either <strong>Prospectus</strong> or by <strong>offer for
                    sale</strong><br /><br /> Let’s see the first one<br /></p>
            <ol>
                <li>Company hires a Merchant Banker or a manage for underwriting the issue (drafting the prospectus
                    )<br /></li>
                <li>Bunty negotiates a deal with the underwriter on basis of the amount to be raised and other aspects
                    of the underwriting document<br /></li>
                <li>Once the deal is final the merchant Banker and company prepares the document
                    (<strong>prospectus</strong>) for registeration with SEBI.</li>
                <li>Once Sebi approves the issue then the date is set and prospectus is released.<br /></li>
            </ol>
            <p><strong>Role of SEBI</strong></p>
            <ol>
                <li>Company trying to get listed needs to submit a draft offer document with sebi.<br /></li>
                <li>Draft Document is the Prospectus at a draft stage.<br /></li>
                <li>SEBI publish the draft for 21 days for public opinion. Final changes are undertaken by merchant
                    banker..<br /></li>
            </ol>
            <p>But what is the <strong>Offer Document</strong><br /><br /> It is an offer document that describes
                company’s agenda and functioning along with the fundamental cash flow statements and balance sheets for
                evaluation. It also has the issue date and issue Price range. <br /> Without the Issue date and price
                draft is called as <strong>red herring</strong><br /><br /></p>
            <p>Now Bunty eagerly waits for <strong>Book Building</strong> (The process to decide the issue price of
                IPO)<br /> under Book Building the merchant banker calculates a price band and the upper limit of this
                band is called <strong>cap</strong> and the lower limit is called <strong>floor</strong> . the Book
                remains open for three days for investors to place bids and based on the data of bids and the
                willingness of investors a price is released called Cut off price,, Again based on Demand and
                Supply.<br /> Now a lot of investors may apply to purchase Bunty’s shares, but most of the time the
                number of shares released is less then the whole demmand. In this case the merchant banker decides about
                who will be alloted shares and who wouldn’t be.<br /><br /></p>
            <p>Let’s see the other way around if I want to subscribe an IPO of Bunty’s company, I was required to pay
                the amount before the allocation of shares, and the money was deducted form my account. Now if I dont
                get the allocation the money would be refunded, but it took time and I lost interest on money in
                meanwhile.<br /> Hence SEBI came up with a Unique Idea called <strong>ASBA</strong> Application
                Supported by Blocked amount. Here the amount would be blocked in my account itself and I would be paid
                interest also, There won’t be issue of refund as on failure of allocation, The amount would be
                unblocked, In case of sucessful allocation, amount would be deducted…<br /><br /></p>
            <p>Let’s see the other method called <strong>offer for sale</strong> <br /><br /></p>
            <ol>
                <li>Bunty or the issuing company sells the whole lot to an intermediary at an agreed price<br /></li>
                <li>The intermediary sells these shares to Public at a price with his margin, here the issuiong company
                    is saved from a tedious porcess as described above but has to agree on a margin grabbed by the
                    intyermediary<br /><br /> Now our own Bunty has become a Big man and if his IPO is subscribed
                    sucessfully then his shares will enter the Secondary market to trade..<br /><br /> But what if Bunty
                    fails to enter the market ??? <br /> well there are 22 regional exchanges where he can get listed
                    for local or OTC placement. Hence the limit is the Sky, All we need is to fly !!!<br /><br /></li>
            </ol>
            <p>Happy Investing</p>
            <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
            <script>
                (function () { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE var d = document, s = d.createElement('script'); s.src = 'https://https-gupta-anubhav12-github-io-fortheloveofnifty.disqus.com/embed.js'; s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date()); (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s); })(); 
            </script> <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments
                    powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
        </content>
        <author>
            <name>Anubhav Gupta</name>
        </author>
        <summary type="html" />
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">P10-What-After-IPO</title>
        <link href="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/10/2020-05-11-What-after-IPO.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"
            title="P10-What-After-IPO" />
        <published>2020-05-10T16:52:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-05-10T16:52:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/10/2020-05-11-What-after-IPO</id>
        <content type="html" xml:base="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/10/2020-05-11-What-after-IPO.html">
            <style>
                header {
                    background-color: rgba(249, 241, 241, 0.7);
                    font-weight: bolder;
                    font-size: larger;
                    font-family: fantasy;
                }

                div {
                    background-image: url("https://i.postimg.cc/y6fw6m3Y/yoann-siloine-dyax-Q-ao-GWY-unsplash.jpg");
                }
            </style>
            <p><strong>post 10</strong> <br /> <strong>Dated</strong>11/5/2020<br /> <strong>What after IPO</strong>
                <br /> <strong>snippet</strong> Today we will see How bunty expands his company and expands his capital
                base..<br /></p>
            <p>So yesterday we saw how Bunty launched an IPO and now his company is listed in the Stock Exchange. Now
                after the IPO bunty needs to raise another round of Capital Expansion. Let’s see the pool of options
                bunty has.<br /></p>
            <p><strong>FPO</strong><br /> Follow on Public Offering is the following round of raising capital from the
                market,It also requires the issue of a Prospectus and can raise money in two ways<br /></p>
            <ol>
                <li><strong>Dilutive</strong> here the company issues new shares and sell them in market.</li>
                <li><strong>NON Dilutive</strong> Here company sells the shares those were privately held.</li>
            </ol>
            <p><strong>Rights Issue</strong><br /> Once bunty is listed on the market using and IPO then he can initiate
                a Rights issue. Here the company gives an offer to it’s existing shareholders to purchase more
                shares.<br /> example a company announces a 5:1 <em>rights issue</em>, this would mean that a
                shareholder having 5 shares can optionally purchase one more, But a person who does not own shares
                previously would not be able to purchase any stake. This method is useful if Bunty want’s to avoid
                diluting the ownership of his company.<br /></p>
            <p><strong>Bonus Issue</strong><br /> As we’ve discussed earlier that Bunty is supposed to share his
                company’s profit as dividned but what if he decides to employ that profit for growth of his
                company??<br /> here Bunty can declare a Bonus Issue where he decides a ratio to give shares free of
                cost to previous shareholders in leiu of Dividend. Example his company declares the bonus of 100:1 then
                each investor holding 100 shares will get 1 share free of cost, Which can be sold in market to obtain
                money that dividend would have given.<br /><br /></p>
            <p>Now with hard work of bunty and his team his company grew too big and share price increased too much, The
                raised price is becoming unaffordable for small investors and the demand is becoming low due to huge
                amount required to purchase a share in market.<br /><br /> Our Intelligent Bunty also has a trick to
                avoid this , He calls for a <strong>Share Split</strong><br /> Here a ratio is divided and the value of
                each share is divided according to that ratio, but the no of shares held by an investor are multiplied
                by the same factor.<br /> Example Bunty had his one share trading at 10,000 rupees a share and investors
                are reluctant to buy a share that costly, also I have 10 shares of his company that I purchased from
                Bholla Singh, Bunty now announces a split of 1:10 meaning value of his one share will reduce to 1000,
                but wait i have 10 shares in my Demat account, They will get multiplied by 10, and I will be now holding
                100 shares for the same value.<br /> The practical Share split is shown Below, the graph gets
                automatically adjusted and behaves like split never happpened by adjusting all the past values,A clear
                drop in Blue colour is seen due to split, and The red one shows the normalized value after the
                split,<br /></p>
            <p><img style="float:left"
                    src="https://i.postimg.cc/FFDCySHz/main-qimg-d0c414b65cd86b752c8f9b17c63ad360.gif" /></p>
            <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
            <script>
                (function () { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE var d = document, s = d.createElement('script'); s.src = 'https://https-gupta-anubhav12-github-io-fortheloveofnifty.disqus.com/embed.js'; s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date()); (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s); })(); 
            </script> <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments
                    powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
        </content>
        <author>
            <name>Anubhav Gupta</name>
        </author>
        <summary type="html" />
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">P8-What-is-a-Share</title>
        <link href="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/09/2020-05-09-What-is-a-Share.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"
            title="P8-What-is-a-Share" />
        <published>2020-05-09T16:52:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-05-09T16:52:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/09/2020-05-09-What-is-a-Share</id>
        <content type="html" xml:base="/fortheloveofnifty/2020/05/09/2020-05-09-What-is-a-Share.html">
            <style>
                header {
                    background-color: rgba(249, 241, 241, 0.7);
                    font-weight: bolder;
                    font-size: larger;
                    font-family: fantasy;
                }

                div {
                    background-image: url("https://i.postimg.cc/y6fw6m3Y/yoann-siloine-dyax-Q-ao-GWY-unsplash.jpg");
                }
            </style>
            <p><strong>post 8</strong> <br /> <strong>Dated</strong>8/5/2020<br /> <strong>What is a Share</strong>
                <br /> <strong>snippet</strong> Today we will discuss the need and significance of securities or shares
                and bonds<br /></p>
            <p>This all starts from the story of Bunty and his Idea to start a company say “Bunty’s Startup”. The
                estimated capital (money) requirement for his dream company is say rupees 10 lakhs, Bunty has only
                <strong>3 Lakhs</strong> and can-not loose time in setting up a company. What he can do??<br /> first
                thought we get is to approach a <em>bank</em> for a <strong>LOAN</strong> but bunty has a credit limit
                or a maximum loan limit of Rupees 3 Lakhs.. He has now managed to collect <strong>6 Lakhs</strong> but
                still require 4 more.<br /> Now Bunty and Bholla Singh are good friends, Bholla Singh promise him to
                give 1 Lakh remaining ,<strong>not as a loan</strong>, but for <strong>equity</strong>. Here Bunty has
                sold a part of his New company to Bholla Singh. Bholla Singh paid 1 Lakh hence has paid 10% of the total
                value of his company which is 10 Lakh. Hence now Bholla singh is a <strong>shareholder</strong> or a
                partial owner of 10% of Bunty’s Company.<br /> Now Bunty still needs 3 lakhs more so he approach several
                more investors to whom he issues shares of his company and make them partial owners and share
                holders.<br /> Now since Bunty does not have a Full ownership of his company so he can not enjoy all the
                profits alone but have to share the profit as per the share holding perentage. So Bholla Singh gets 10%
                of total profits and Babla also gets 10%. Same goes for everyone with their respective holdings. This
                profit is Called Dividend.<br /> But wait <strong>Bunty can counter Loss also</strong> in that case the
                losses will also be divided similar to profits,<br /> but what about that loan that Bunty Took?? the
                bank wont see wether Bunty is in profit or in loss, Bank would want it’s <strong>money back with
                    interest</strong> <br /> so this is the basic difference of a Debt( the one like Loan) and
                Equity(shares) instruments.<br /> If I am an investor and I am willing to share profits of a company at
                the risk of facing losses too, I will invest in Equity segments or Shares.<br /> But if I am person who
                isn’t a Risk taker,,I will go with investing in debt instruments like Bonds and debentures. <br /> The
                equity investments have an unlimited scope as compared to a Debt instrument because even if a company
                touches sky and generates huge profits, The interest at a debt instrument would be payed as fixed on the
                issuing norms, whereas the shareholders will share that huge profits and return with stuffed
                pockets.<br /><br /> Now shares are traded on a stock Exchange after their First Issue, Their price is
                defined in three categories .<br /> Every Share or a Bond has a <strong>Face Value</strong>, or the
                Value which corresponds to stake in company.<br /></p>
            <ol>
                <li>If the Security (we refer to equity and debt collectively as securities) is being traded lower than
                    it’s face value the it’s said to be sold <strong>at discount</strong> <br /></li>
                <li>If the security is sold at a value equal to the face value then it’s said to be <strong>sold at
                        par</strong><br /></li>
                <li>If the security is sold at a value greater than face value then it’s said to be sold <strong>at
                        premium</strong><br /><br /></li>
            </ol>
            <p>but wait why does the price fluctuate from the Face Value???<br /><br /> let’s go Back to the out
                favoutrite Bunty, Say Bholla singh want his money back but bunty isn’t ready to <strong>buyback</strong>
                his shares. So Bholla Singh comes to me and I have interest in Bunty’s Company (Due to large Profits he
                is generating) and I am willing to enter the shareholding. But Bholla Singh has shares, and I am now his
                customer. Bholla singh Wants amount of 1.25 Lakhs for the stake of 10% of Bunty’s Company of 10 Lakh
                because Bunty is in profit. We crack the deal and now I have brought the Shares at premium <strong>due
                    to the Reputation of Bunty’s Company</strong> <br /><br /> This is how news related to a company
                changes it’s supply demmand and regulates it’s price. <br /><br /> Tommorow We will hack into Life of
                BUNTY to find out how he can list his company on a stock Exchange<br /><br /></p>
            <p><strong>disclaimer</strong> Bholla SIngh , Bunty, Babbla , Laddoo are not fictional Charaters but my
                Friends, Who might get offended after reading this, But they are cool people. :):)..<br /><br /></p>
            <p>Happy Learning</p>
            <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
            <script>
                (function () { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE var d = document, s = d.createElement('script'); s.src = 'https://https-gupta-anubhav12-github-io-fortheloveofnifty.disqus.com/embed.js'; s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date()); (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s); })(); 
            </script> <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments
                    powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
        </content>
        <author>
            <name>Anubhav Gupta</name>
        </author>
        <summary type="html" />
    </entry>
</feed>